<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<records start="0" rows="1" numfound="1">
    <record status="Completed" released="Y">
        <site_input_code>KBASE</site_input_code>
        <hidden>false</hidden>
        <osti_id>1778009</osti_id>
        <dataset_type></dataset_type>
        <title>Gulf of Mexico blue hole harbors high levels of novel microbial lineages</title>
        <authors>
            <author role="primary">
                <first_name>Nastassia</first_name>
                <last_name>Patin</last_name>
                <affiliation_name>Univ. of Miami, Miami, FL (United States)
                    University of Miami Rosenstiel School of Marine and Atmospheric Science</affiliation_name>
                <orcid_id>0000000185227682</orcid_id>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <related_resource>Patin, N.V., Dietrich, Z.A., Stancil, A. et al. Gulf of Mexico blue hole
            harbors high levels of novel microbial lineages. ISME J (2021).
            https://doi.org/10.1038/s41396-021-00917-x</related_resource>
        <product_nos>None</product_nos>
        <product_type>DA</product_type>
        <contract_nos>N/A</contract_nos>
        <other_identifying_numbers></other_identifying_numbers>
        <originating_research_org>Center for Microbial Dynamics and Infection, Georgia Institute of
            Technology, Atlanta, GA, USA; School of Biological
            Sciences, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA, USA; Southwest Fisheries Science
            Center, National Marine
            Fisheries Service, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, La Jolla, CA, USA;
            Cooperative Institute for Marine
            and Atmospheric Studies, Rosenstiel School of Marine and Atmospheric Science, University
            of Miami, Miami, FL, USA;
            Ocean Chemistry and Ecosystems Division, Atlantic Oceanographic and Meteorological
            Laboratory, National Oceanic and
            Atmospheric Administration, Miami, FL, USA</originating_research_org>
        <availability></availability>
        <collaboration_names></collaboration_names>
        <publication_date>02/21/2021</publication_date>
        <language>English</language>
        <country>US</country>
        <sponsor_org>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Office of Exploration and
            Research</sponsor_org>
        <subject_categories_code>59 BASIC BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES</subject_categories_code>
        <keywords>metagenomics, marine microbial communities, MAGs, metagenome-assembled genomes,</keywords>
        <accession_num></accession_num>
        <description>xploration of oxygen-depleted marine environments has consistently revealed
            novel microbial taxa and metabolic capabilities that expand our understanding of
            microbial evolution and ecology. Marine blue holes are shallow karst formations
            characterized by low oxygen and high organic matter content. They are logistically
            challenging to sample, and thus our understanding of their biogeochemistry and microbial
            ecology is limited. We present a metagenomic and geochemical characterization of
            Amberjack Hole on the Florida continental shelf (Gulf of Mexico). Dissolved oxygen
            became depleted at the hole’s rim (32 m water depth), remained low but detectable in an
            intermediate hypoxic zone (40–75 m), and then increased to a secondary peak before
            falling below detection in the bottom layer (80–110 m), concomitant with increases in
            nutrients, dissolved iron, and a series of sequentially more reduced sulfur species.
            Microbial communities in the bottom layer contained heretofore undocumented levels of
            the recently discovered phylum Woesearchaeota (up to 58% of the community), along with
            lineages in the bacterial Candidate Phyla Radiation (CPR). Thirty-one high-quality
            metagenome-assembled genomes (MAGs) showed extensive biochemical capabilities for sulfur
            and nitrogen cycling, as well as for resisting and respiring arsenic. One
            uncharacterized gene associated with a CPR lineage differentiated hypoxic from anoxic
            zone communities. Overall, microbial communities and geochemical profiles were stable
            across two sampling dates in the spring and fall of 2019. The blue hole habitat is a
            natural marine laboratory that provides opportunities for sampling taxa with
            under-characterized but potentially important roles in redox-stratified microbial
            processes.</description>
        <site_url>https://kbase.us/n/86723/65/</site_url>
        <related_identifiers>
            <detail>
                <related_identifier>10.6084/m9.figshare.12644045.v1</related_identifier>
                <related_identifier_type>DOI</related_identifier_type>
                <relation_type>IsIdenticalTo</relation_type>
            </detail>
            <detail>
                <related_identifier>10.1038/s41396-021-00917-x</related_identifier>
                <related_identifier_type>DOI</related_identifier_type>
                <relation_type>References</relation_type>
            </detail>
            <detail>
                <related_identifier>10.6084/m9.figshare.12644081.v1</related_identifier>
                <related_identifier_type>DOI</related_identifier_type>
                <relation_type>IsIdenticalTo</relation_type>
            </detail>
            <detail>
                <related_identifier>10.6084/m9.figshare.12644042.v1</related_identifier>
                <related_identifier_type>DOI</related_identifier_type>
                <relation_type>IsIdenticalTo</relation_type>
            </detail>
            <detail>
                <related_identifier>10.6084/m9.figshare.12644048.v1</related_identifier>
                <related_identifier_type>DOI</related_identifier_type>
                <relation_type>IsIdenticalTo</relation_type>
            </detail>
            <detail>
                <related_identifier>10.6084/m9.figshare.12644018.v3</related_identifier>
                <related_identifier_type>DOI</related_identifier_type>
                <relation_type>IsIdenticalTo</relation_type>
            </detail>
            <detail>
                <related_identifier>10.6084/m9.figshare.12644060.v1</related_identifier>
                <related_identifier_type>DOI</related_identifier_type>
                <relation_type>IsIdenticalTo</relation_type>
            </detail>
            <detail>
                <related_identifier>10.6084/m9.figshare.12644051.v1</related_identifier>
                <related_identifier_type>DOI</related_identifier_type>
                <relation_type>IsIdenticalTo</relation_type>
            </detail>
        </related_identifiers>
        <date_first_submitted>2021-04-19</date_first_submitted>
        <date_last_submitted>2021-04-19</date_last_submitted>
        <entry_date>2021-04-19</entry_date>
        <doi status="COMPLETED">10.25982/86723.65/1778009</doi>
        <doi_infix>86723.65</doi_infix>
        <file_extension></file_extension>
        <software_needed></software_needed>
        <dataset_size></dataset_size>
        <contact_name>Zachary Crockett, KBase Outreach Team</contact_name>
        <contact_org>Department of Energy Systems Biology Knowledgebase (KBase)</contact_org>
        <contact_email>crockettzr@ornl.gov</contact_email>
        <contact_phone>4235062084</contact_phone>
        <othnondoe_contract_nos></othnondoe_contract_nos>
    </record>
</records>
