<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<records start="0" rows="1" numfound="1">
    <record status="Completed" released="Y">
        <site_input_code>KBASE</site_input_code>
        <hidden>false</hidden>
        <osti_id>1828592</osti_id>
        <dataset_type>GD</dataset_type>
        <title>The moderately defficient enzyme: Catalysis-related damage in vivo and its repair</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <first_name>Christopher</first_name>
                <middle_name>S</middle_name>
                <last_name>Henry</last_name>
                <affiliation_name>Argonne National Lab. (ANL), Argonne, IL (United States)</affiliation_name>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <related_resource></related_resource>
        <product_nos>None</product_nos>
        <product_type>DA</product_type>
        <contract_nos>N/A</contract_nos>
        <other_identifying_numbers></other_identifying_numbers>
        <originating_research_org>Argonne National Laboratory (ANL), Argonne, IL (United States); US
            Department of Energy Systems Biology Knowledgebase</originating_research_org>
        <availability></availability>
        <collaboration_names></collaboration_names>
        <publication_date>11/02/2021</publication_date>
        <language>English</language>
        <country>US</country>
        <sponsor_org>USDOE Office of Science (SC), Biological and Environmental Research (BER)</sponsor_org>
        <subject_categories_code>59 BASIC BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES</subject_categories_code>
        <keywords></keywords>
        <accession_num></accession_num>
        <description>Enzymes have in vivo lifespans. Analysis of lifespans – lifetime totals of
            catalytic turnovers – suggests that non-survivable collateral chemical damage from the
            very reactions that enzymes catalyze is a common but underdiagnosed cause of enzyme
            death. Analysis also implies that many enzymes are moderately deficient in that their
            active-site regions are not naturally as hardened against such collateral damage as they
            could be, leaving room for improvement by rational design or directed evolution. Enzyme
            lifespan might also be improved by engineering systems that repair otherwise fatal
            active-site damage, of which a handful are known and more are inferred to exist.
            Unfortunately, the data needed to design and execute such improvements is lacking: there
            are too few measurements of in vivo lifespan, and existing information on the extent,
            nature, and mechanisms of active-site damage and repair during normal enzyme operation
            is too scarce, anecdotal, and speculative to act on. Fortunately, advances in
            proteomics, metabolomics, cheminformatics, comparative genomics, and structural
            biochemistry now empower a systematic, data-driven approach to identify, predict, and
            validate instances of active-site damage and its repair. These capabilities would be
            practically useful in enzyme redesign and improvement of in-use stability, and could
            change thinking about which enzymes die young in vivo, and why.</description>
        <site_url>https://kbase.us/n/95771/20/</site_url>
        <date_first_submitted>2021-11-02</date_first_submitted>
        <date_last_submitted>2021-11-02</date_last_submitted>
        <entry_date>2021-11-02</entry_date>
        <doi status="COMPLETED">10.25982/95771.20/1828592</doi>
        <doi_infix>95771.20</doi_infix>
        <file_extension></file_extension>
        <software_needed></software_needed>
        <dataset_size></dataset_size>
        <contact_name>Zachary Crockett, KBase Outreach Team</contact_name>
        <contact_org>Department of Energy Systems Biology Knowledgebase (KBase)</contact_org>
        <contact_email>crockettzr@ornl.gov</contact_email>
        <contact_phone>4235062084</contact_phone>
        <othnondoe_contract_nos></othnondoe_contract_nos>
    </record>
</records>
